Cameron Burdsall

408-775-4741 San Jose, CA clburdsall@scu.edu

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cameron-burdsall-010695104/

Website: http://students.engr.scu.edu/~cburdsal/

OBJECTIVE: To find an internship position in which I can contribute my Computer Engineering education and several years of IT experience and in addition to a passionate work ethic and effective knowledge of software engineering principles.

EDUCATION:

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Engineering, Santa Clara University

Rising Senior, Expected Graduation: June 2021

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

Programming Languages: C/C++, Python, HTML/CSS, Java, SQL, JavaScript, Prolog,

ARM Assembly, MATLAB, Verilog

Software: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Intel Quartus, Visual Studio, Eclipse, Brackets IO, Xilinx Vivado

Platforms: Windows, macOS, Ubuntu, Centos, UNIX/Linux Terminal, Windows Command Line **Skills:** Data Structures, Algorithms, OOP, Troubleshooting/Debugging, Socket Programming

Technologies: Various Java, Python, and C++ libraries, Ticketing Systems, Database Systems (MS SQL)

PROJECTS:

Java Test Taking Application

April 2020

- Led 3-person team to create an application that tests students and keeps track of their grades
- 3 Layered application with a UI (Java Swing), Business layer, and Persistence layer

C Webserver February 2020

- Multithreaded C Program that allows multiple clients to simultaneously connect to a server
- Uses Linux system calls to establish a TCP connection which sends packets which constitute a file

AI TwitterBot: https://twitter.com/camburdbot

June 2020

- Python program that uses Markov chains to generate realistic content from a set of quotations
- Automatically generates a string with a random font and overlays on top of a randomly selected image

Sales Database/Site: http://students.engr.scu.edu/~cburdsal/COEN178Project/sales.html

May 2020

- Designed and implemented a SQL Server database for a sales system
- Created a website interface that is connected to the database using PHP code that allows users to sign up, place orders, and view product information

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Pure Storage, Remote

Software Automation Intern

June 2020 - Sept 2020

- Created system that automatically gathers information regarding SaaS usage and spending and organizes it into a single reporting dashboard on Tableau
- Wrote Python programs hosted on a Docker container to pull data and created a SQL database to store data

Santa Clara University, Santa Clara, CA

Help Desk Analyst/Field Support Technician

July 2018 – March 2020

- Provided technical support for students, faculty, and staff
- Performed troubleshooting of hardware and software issues, research potential solutions

RELEVENT TECHNICAL COURSEWORK:

- OO Analysis, Design, & Programming
- OO Data Structures
- Computer Networks
- Computer Architecture
- Electric Circuits
- Logic Design
- Artificial Intelligence
- Theory of Algorithms
- Embedded Systems
- Database Management Systems
- Probability & Statistics
- Differential Equations
- Linear Algebra
- Operating Systems

AFFILIATIONS

- Member, Association for Computing Machinery
- Member, Pi Kappa Alpha Fraternity
- Hackathon Participant, Hack for Humanity 2020

September 2019 - Present January 2018 – Present February 2020